美国空军的F-22猛禽隐形战斗机进行了一次重大的升级
The US Air Force's F-22 Raptor stealth fighter has received a major upgrade
这款标志性的战斗机即将迈入第三个十年的服役
as the iconic fighter approaches its third decade of frontline service
面临退役
and retirement.
在本视频中 我们将详细了解这次升级
In this video, we take a closer look at the upgrade,
以及它的潜在用途和对空军的意义
its potential uses, and its role for the Air Force.
F-22的单架成本高达3亿美元
The F-22, costing $300 million per unit,
其开发历程漫长
had a protracted development journey.
它起源于1980年代的先进战术战斗机计划
It originated from the Advanced Tactical Fighter Initiative in the 1980s
1990年首次亮相 并于2005年完成开发
made its demonstrator debut in 1990, and completed development in 2005.
猛禽战斗机于2006年首次在日本部署
The Raptor was first deployed to Japan in 2006
并于2012年完成生产 总共只建造了195架
and finished production in 2012, with only 195 planes built.
它首次参战
It saw combat for the first time
在对抗伊斯兰国的空中战役中 2014年
during the air campaign against the Islamic State in 2014.
如今 F-22定期部署到太平洋地区以威慑中国
Today, the F-22 routinely deploys to the Pacific region to deter China
同时也部署到欧洲以威慑俄罗斯
and to Europe to deter Russia.
尽管它外形未来感十足、难以探测 性能也极为出色
Despite its futuristic, hard-to-detect shape and blistering performance,
但本质上
in its bones
F-22是一款冷战时代的战斗机
the F-22 is a Cold War jet.
洛克希德设计它是为了在欧洲的基地对抗苏联
Lockheed designed it to battle the Soviet Union from bases in Europe
因此 续航能力不足实际上并不是问题
meaning poor endurance wasn't really an issue.
这架战斗机仅依靠内部燃油 航程大约为600英里
The fighter can range just 600 miles or so on internal fuel,
足以在德国和波兰上空展开作战
plenty far enough to fight over Germany and Poland.
F-22猛禽的隐形技术与机动性的独特结合
The F-22 Raptor's unique combination of stealth and maneuverability,
一套出色的内部空对空导弹库
a decent internal air-to-air missile magazine
再加上一门20毫米的炮 使其成为最具优势的战斗机之一
and a 20mm gun make it one of the most dominant fighters today.
此外 这架战斗机经过数十年的逐步升级
Additionally, the fighter has been slowly upgraded over the decades
以维持其技术优势
to contain a qualitative edge
超越其他国家的顶级空中优势战斗机
over other nations' top air superiority fighters
比如中国的
like the People's Republic of China,
J-20
还有俄罗斯的苏-57
and Russia's Su-57.
美国将中国视为主要威胁
with the United States considering China the pacing threat
因其对台湾的威胁
due to its designs on Taiwan
和其他侵略行动
and other aggressive actions
人们担心90年代设计的F-22猛禽可能面临困难
there is concern that the circa-90s design F-22 Raptor may have difficulty
在与2000年代的新型战斗机对抗时
going up against the 2000s design
成都J-20
Chengdu J-20.
然而 J-20的设计是为了应对
However, the J-20 was designed to help deal with the tyranny of distance
太平洋的地理距离问题
in the Pacific
而F-22的设计则主要针对欧洲战场
while the F-22 was designed more for the European theatre
威胁愈发迫近
where threats are closer.
尽管下一代空中优势战斗机
Despite the fact that the next generation air dominance fighter
已在深入研发
is well into development
不断增加
the increasing numbers
且日益先进的歼-20战斗机让美国空军感到紧张
and ever-improving J-20 jets are making the U.S. Air Force nervous.
尽管F-22猛禽的航程为460海里
Although the F-22 Raptor has a published range of 460 nautical miles
大约530英里
which is about 530 miles
并留有超巡航的余地
with some margin for supercruise
F-22在太平洋作战需要更远的航程
more range is needed for the F-22 to operate in the Pacific.
例如 五角大楼在台湾战争中最近的空军基地是
For example, the Pentagon's closest airbase for a war over Taiwan,
位于日本的嘉手纳基地
Kadena in Japan,
距离约450英里
is 450 miles away.
如果嘉手纳基地被中国导弹摧毁
If Kadena is knocked out by Chinese missiles,
离它最近的主要基地是美泽
the next closest major base, Misawa,
该基地同样在日本 距离达1400英里
also in Japan, is 1,400 miles away.
在对台湾的空战策划中 理由是有的
It's not for no reason that in planning for an air war over Taiwan
美国空军官员日益忽视F-22战斗机
USAF officers increasingly disregard the F-22s
而转而
and other fighters
计算最佳作战方式
and instead calculate optimal ways
远程重型轰炸机
for the service's long-range heavy bombers
以应对中国的入侵部队
to engage a Chinese invasion force.
F-22的作战范围为530英里 显然不足
The F-22 combat range of 530 miles is insufficient,
且美国空军现有装备中没有隐形空中加油机
and with no stealthy aerial refuelers in the U.S. Air Force's inventory
这会对航程达到700英里的歼-20造成困扰
this is going to pose a problem with J-20s with a 700-mile range
歼-20的设计目标是寻找加油机
designed to seek out refuelers
以及其他支援机
and other support aircraft at range.
鉴于这些重要的局限性和不断变化的威胁
Recognizing these critical limitations and the evolving threats
空军正在重资投入
the Air Force is making significant investments
以提升F-22的能力
to enhance the F-22's capabilities.
《空天力量》杂志称 空军
The Air Force, according to Air and Space Forces magazine,
计划投入78亿美元
plans to spend $7.8 billion
用于F-22
on the F-22
2024年至2029年
between 2024 and 2029.
这些资金将用于研发、测试和升级
The money is going towards research and development, testing and upgrades.
因此 有来源指出
Thus, according to some sources
最新的 F-22 采用了一种新的隐形燃油箱
the latest F-22s are due to the new stealthy fuel tanks,
官方称其为
officially known as
低阻油箱和支架 简称 LDTP
Low Drag Tank and Pylon, or LDTP
这些油箱最初的设计目的是为了提高隐形能力
which were originally designed to be stealthier
其气动效率优于现有的 600 加仑燃油箱
and more aerodynamically efficient than the current 600-gallon fuel tanks.
LDTP 旨在支持外部油箱的超音速飞行
The LDTP was intended to allow supersonic flight with external tanks,
同时延长猛禽的飞行范围
while extending the Raptor's range.
据说 支架配备了智能
The pylons are reportedly equipped with intelligent
齿轮气动技术
rack-and-pinion pneumatic technology
能够实现精确弹射
that allows for controlled ejection.
在2023财年的预算申请中
In its fiscal year 2023 budget request
美国空军表示 F-22 LDTP
the U.S. Air Force noted that the F-22 LDTPs
配备了先进技术设计
feature advanced technological designs
能够提升续航能力
that could provide increased endurance
同时在保持致命性和生存能力的前提下
and range while maintaining lethality
提高射程 这是维持空中优势的关键
and survivability, critical attributes for maintaining
此外
air superiority, In addition
F-22猛禽将升级红外搜索能力
the F-22 Raptor will receive infrared search
并通过两个翼尖舱增强跟踪能力
and track capability via two wingtip pods.
这些系统 顾名思义 可以探测热特征
These systems, as the name implies, detect heat signatures
这让像Raptor这样的隐形战斗机能够定位敌机
allowing a stealth fighter like the Raptor to locate enemy aircraft
而不暴露自身信号
without revealing its presence via radar signals.
这也让战斗机能利用排气的热量
It also allows a fighter to use the heat from its exhaust
追踪隐形目标
to track stealthy enemies.
根据2025年美国空军预算提案
According to the proposed 2025 U.S. Air Force budget
其目标是保持空中优势
the intent is to maintain air superiority
并确保在战斗中始终占据先机
and preserve first look, first shot,
另外 还确保有第一击能力
and first kill capability.
另一个升级内容是
Another upgrade,
根据2024年3月27日的《空天部队杂志》
according to the March 27th, 2024 Air and Spaces Force Magazine,
再次提到
and again
2025年美国空军预算的提案
the proposed 2025 U.S. Air Force budget
指的是受控接收模式天线
is the Controlled Reception Pattern Antenna
用来抵御GPS干扰
which will counter GPS jamming.
这将与GPS天线升级的工作同步进行
This will go alongside efforts to upgrade the GPS antenna
这与其它无线电升级相辅相成
which coincides with other radio upgrades
以确保战斗机间的信息安全共享
to ensure secure information sharing between combat aircraft.
根据2025年美国空军预算的安排
According to the 2025 US Air Force budget
还有一项升级是进行研究
one more upgrade is to perform studies
以及为先进威胁警告接收器设计原型
and prototyping for an advanced threat warning receiver.
这样 F-22就能更有效地探测敌方雷达
This way, the F-22 can detect adversary radars better.
还有改进F-22识别能力的努力
There are also efforts to improve the F-22's ability to learn
来袭导弹
about approaching missiles.
在这里你可以看到猛禽如何通过发射照明弹来进行反应
Here you can see how Raptor can respond by deploying flares
这正是F-22表演队去年在航展上所做的
as the F-22 demo team did at an air show last year.
提到导弹 F-22猛禽是首款武器平台
Speaking of missiles, the F-22 Raptor is the first weapons platform
它将接收绝密的AIM-260联合先进战术导弹
intended to receive the top-secret AIM-260 Joint Advanced Tactical Missile,
简称JATM
or JATM for short.
这种新型空对空导弹的射程比AIM-120D更长
The new air-to-air missile has a longer range than the AIM-120D
并且改进了导引头
and an improved seeker head.
AIM-260的开发在2019年首次公开
The development of the AIM-260 was first unveiled in 2019
而至少从2017年起就已开始研发
and has been in the works at least since 2017.
新型远程空对空导弹的目的在于取代AIM-120
The goal of the new long-range air-to-air missile is to replace the AIM-120
AIM-RAM 并对抗中国PL-15导弹的威胁
AIM-RAM and counter the threat posed by the Chinese PL-15 missile
同时避免其他国家在射程上超过AIM-120
while preventing foreign threats
让其能够在射程上超过AIM-120
from being able to outrange the AIM-120.
预算请求中还提到其他升级
Other upgrades mentioned in the budget request
包括模式5的友我识别系统
include a Mode 5 identification friend
or foe,
LINK-16系统、新的作战计划
LINK-16 system, a new operational fight program,
先进的雷达电子保护和开放架构的加密通信系统
advanced radar electronic protection, open system architecture,
还有新的加密无线电
and new encrypted radios.
除了升级 高层空军领导人描述了
Beyond the upgrade, senior Air Force leaders have described
F-22项目
the F-22 program now
到2030年
through 2030
为下一代空中优势战斗机
as a bridge to the next-generation air dominance fighter
及其相关系统奠定基础
and its family of systems.
有多个音调说明 在F-22逐渐退役期间开发的技术
and several have said that technologies being developed
针对F-22逐渐退役的技术
for the F-22 in its waning service years
将直接应用于下一代空中优势计划（NGAD）
will be directly applicable to NGAD.
预算预计F-22机队将减少32架
The budget assumes the F-22 fleet will be reduced by 32 aircraft
降至约153架
to about 153 planes
但文件显示 只有142架将获得
but the documents say only 142 will receive
全面升级
the full line-up of improvements.
空军计划剥离的32架战斗机为Block 20配置
The 32 jets the Air Force wants to divest are of Block 20 configuration
空军部长弗兰克·肯德尔表示 每架费用将超过
and Air Force Secretary Frank Kendall has said it would cost more than
5000万美元
$50 million each
升级到Block 30 即当前最新标准
to bring them up to Block 30, the most up-to-date standard.
空军优先将这笔钱用于提升新型战机
The Air Force prefers to spend that money on making the younger models
对预期威胁的能力
more capable against the anticipated threat,
主要是空对空挑战
primarily the air-to-air challenge
由中国第五代战斗机带来的
posed by China's fifth-generation fighters
以及先进的空对空导弹
and advanced air-to-air missiles.
尽管计划减少F-22机队
Despite plans to reduce the F-22 fleet
对升级剩余战机的决心
the commitment to upgrading the remaining jets
显示了空军的坚定决心
demonstrates the Air Force's determination
以确保“猛禽”战斗机持续相关性
to keep the Raptor relevant.
这是否意味着延长其服役时间
Whether this means extending its service life
或将其先进技术应用于下一代战斗机
or integrating its advancements into the next generation of fighters
F-22的传承仍在不断发展
the F-22's legacy continues to evolve.
随着空军应对这些挑战
As the Air Force navigates the challenges
有一点是肯定的
one thing is certain
F-22猛禽是美国空防战略的重要组成部分
the F-22 Raptor remains a critical component
of America's air defense strategy,
准备在新的对手面前灵活应对 持续表现出色
poised to adapt and excel in the face of new adversaries.
你觉得这个升级怎么样？
And what do you think about this upgrade?
在下方评论告诉我们你的看法哦！
Let us know in the comments below.
如果你喜欢这个视频
Also, if you enjoyed this video
一定要点赞和订阅我们的频道
don't forget to like it, subscribe to the channel
并且记得开启通知 这样就不会错过新视频了
and turn on notifications so you don't miss any new videos.
感谢你的观看 我们下次再见！
and thanks for watching.